紙牌屋
前情提要
翻譯   草草
時間軸   Ans
后期   餓得慌
校對  草草
顧問  老杜
總監  草草
紙牌屋
第六季  第一集
原創翻譯  雙語字幕
最新連載海外影視劇下載
請登陸 www.YYeTs.com
僅供交流學習  禁止商用盈利
還有時間
弗蘭西斯
一個總統安葬另一個總統
試印
安德伍德總統獨立日講話
深切緬懷
雷格·E·凱蒂[弗萊迪飾演者]
吉姆·泰恩斯[燈光師]
那女孩對你說了什么
What did the girl say to you?
她說她希望我死  而你當上總統
She said she hopes I die and that you become the president.
我希望一個女人入主白宮
I want a woman in the White House.
我們需要你讓自己跟佐伊·巴恩斯的死掛上鉤
We need you to implicate yourself in the death of Zoe Barnes.
我不覺得你丈夫該做主導
I don't think your husband should be front and center.
我只想讓弗蘭西斯·安德伍德進監獄
What I want is for Francis Underwood to go to jail.
我有罪
I'm guilty.
我殺了佐伊·巴恩斯
I killed Zoe Barnes.
你們都已經利用我太久了
You have all used me far long enough.
所以我將辭去美國總統一職
So I shall resign the office of President of the United States.
你讓我把丑出盡了
You made me look absolutely ridiculous.
-不  克萊爾  -毫無準備  稀里糊涂
- No! Claire. - Ill-prepared and ignorant.
離我的正式辭職只有幾小時了
We're a few hours away from my official resignation...
而你還沒答應赦免我
and you still have not agreed to pardon me.
我在看副總統的名單
I was going over our list for vice president.
我問過的許多人都說我最合適
A lot of the people I spoke to suggested me.
如今真難知道能相信誰
It's hard to know who to trust these days.
如果她不赦免我
If she doesn't pardon me...
我就殺了她
I'll kill her.
該我了
My turn.
站住  克萊爾·黑爾  站住
Stop. Claire Hale. Stop!
"我想炸了她的眼球
"I'd like to fry her eyeballs.
如果沒有別人敢殺了總統  我就去
If no one else steps up to kill the president, I will.
還當做一份美差"
I'd enjoy it."
這是一條北達科他州的推文
A tweet out of North Dakota.
還有嗎
What else?
"上帝從未想要一個女人統治這片土地
"God never intended a woman to rule this land.
她是反基督
She is the anti-Christ.
-還是猶太人"  -猶太人
- And a Jew." - A Jew?
-我們真有必要聽這些嗎  -是的
- Do we really need to hear all of this? - Yes.
一篇未發表的社論
An unpublished editorial.
有個人拿槍指著你的肖像
Someone pointing a gun at your likeness.
網上還有好多這種東西  包括
Lots of other online stuff, including a...
一個比賽
contest...
比什么
For?
比最有創意的殺你的辦法
For the most creative way to kill you.
哪種方法贏了
And the winner?
我不太想說  女士
Rather not say, ma'am.
我想聽  把報告給我  里克
I want to hear. Just hand me the report, Rick.
基本上是  把你剝皮
It involves, essentially, skinning you.
把你的身體切成數塊
Cutting your body into dozens of pieces
然后擺成美國國旗的形狀
and arranging them in the shape of the American flag.
肉做白條  血做紅條
Flesh for the white stripes, blood for the red.
還有嗎
What else?
很多包含C打頭詞的威脅  女士
Lot of threats involving the C-word, ma'am.
好多好多C打頭的那個詞  很不幸
Lots and lots of the C-word, unfortunately.
-是"克萊爾"嗎  -單子很長
- You mean Claire? - It's a long list.
如果您真想聽  那我...
If you really want me to, I'll--
我不是第一個遭遇威脅的總統
Listen, I am not the first president to face threats.
我知道弗蘭西斯那時  一天里能有好多
I know with Francis, sometimes there were several a day.
情況差不多嗎
Is it about the same
我們現在面臨的威脅
what we're dealing with here?
這...
It's...
數量明顯上升
significantly up.
上升多少
By how much?
你上任以來  每天收到的威脅
There are roughly four times as many threats
大概是之前的四倍
on any given day since you took office.
而弗蘭西斯死后又翻了一番
Now it's twice that since Francis died.
我以為大家都喜歡寡婦呢
I thought everyone loves a widow.
如果她還是三軍統帥可能就不喜歡了吧
Not if she's also Commander-in-Chief, I guess.
這些人并不理智  總統女士
These are not rational people, Madam President.
但女士  就今天的威脅而言
But, ma'am, as far as today's threat,
關于你的第一次公開露面
regarding your first scheduled appearance--
我們要取消
We're canceling the appearance.
我們不能取消
We're not canceling.
那是軍事基地
It's a military base.
那對于總統該是世界上最安全的地方了
That's got to be the safest place on Earth for a president.
一個身份未知的士兵做出了嚴重威脅...
An anonymous soldier has made a serious threat--
"要代表全美國
"To shoot me in the cunt
給我的屄來一槍"
on behalf of the United States of America."
是的  馬克  我聽說了
Yes, Mark, I heard.
這個威脅并未證實
The threat's unconfirmed.
他說他是今天出征的士兵之一
He says he's among those shipping out today.
誰都能這么說
Anyone can claim that.
還說你無權向敘利亞宣戰
And that you have no right waging war in Syria.
尤其是你
You, in particular.
我們還是別去了  里克  你說是吧
I think we stay away. Rick, don't you agree?
并無證據表明這威脅可信  是吧  里克
There's no proof the threat is credible. Isn't that right, Rick?
我們的情報部門正在調查
Our intelligence division is investigating,
先遣隊已經去了
and the advance team is already there,
但至少要一天
but it'll take at least a day
才能把基地查一遍
to comb through that base.
我認為副總統的提議是最佳選擇
I think what the vice president says is the best course.
或許到明天  你就能...
Maybe by tomorrow you could--
明天就不是獨立日了
Tomorrow is the fifth of July.
-是  女士  -那你說我怎么辦
- Yes, ma'am. - So what do you suggest I do?
祝大家遲到的國慶節快樂嗎
Wish the nation a happy belated birthday?
我們只是擔心你的安全...
Our only concern is your safety--
不能取消
We're not cancelling.
我要讓那些士兵上戰場
I am sending those soldiers onto a battlefield.
美國史上第一位女性總統
The first female president of the United States
才不要在7月4日這天被人嚇得說不出話
is not gonna keep her mouth shut on the Fourth of fucking July.
蓋拉格中將也能理解的
Lieutenant General Gallagher would understand.
我可以替你出席
I could appear instead.
-替你講話  -停下
- Speak for you. - Stop.
你擔心的是我的安全
Is it my safety that concerns you,
還是我可能背書蓋拉格
or my potential endorsement of Gallagher?
當然是你的安全第一
Your safety first, of course.
但單提她  這是挑釁
But singling her out, that's a provocation.
那又如何
And so?
我就不能刺激下他們嗎
I can't provoke them?
你在支持一個謝潑德家族反對的
You're forwarding a candidate the Shepherds are against,
家鄉州候選人
in their home state.
-經過了數月的協商  -這不是協商
- After months of negotiation. - This is not a negotiation,
這是最后通牒  簽署法案  否則
this is an ultimatum. Sign the bill or what?
否則什么  馬克
Or what, Mark?
弗蘭西斯想給他的基金會拉資助時
When Francis was looking to finance his foundation,
你為什么給他介紹了比爾和安奈特
why did you point him towards Bill and Annette?
我沒有  是雷蒙德·塔斯克安排的
I didn't. Raymond Tusk arranged it.
也或者是他們聯系了他
Or maybe they reached out to him?
我不記得了
I don't remember.
有什么關系呢  他們現在跟你合作了
I-- What does it matter? They're working with you now.
我要直接見謝潑德兄妹
I need to meet with the Shepherds directly.
總統女士
Madam President.
我去基地前先見他們一面
I'll see them before my appearance at the base.
-不行  -什么
- You can't. - I what?
我會通知他們的
I'll let them know.
謝謝
Thank you.
您4:45要到基地
You're due at the base by 4:45,
然后8:30回來這里
which will have you back here by 8:30.
煙火秀9點過后開始
The fireworks show begins right after nine.
《紐約觀察家》想請您過下這些照片
And the Examiner would love your okay on the photos.
那個聲音的來源查出什么進展了嗎
Is there any progress on the source of the sound?
總務管理局還在調查
The GSA is still looking into it.
他們在檢查樓上樓下的地板
They're checking the floorboards above and below,
-以防...  -我不想再等了
- in case there's-- - I don't want to wait anymore.
請轉告行政管家
Please tell the executive housekeeper
把前總統的東西收拾好
I'd like the former president's belongings packed up.
我會去處理的
I'll have it taken care of.
他多年前對你們說的那句話是不對的
It's not true what he told you all those years ago.
痛苦有兩種  一種讓你變強  一種毫無價值
That there are two kinds, useful and useless.
其實只有一種
There's only one kind.
痛苦就是痛苦
Pain is pain.
弗蘭西斯
Francis...
我和你結束了
I'm done with you.
瞧
There.
沒有痛苦了
No more pain.
你一整天都做這個嗎
You do this all day?
我在接受精神科觀察  賽斯
I'm under psychiatric observation, Seth.
就得這樣
This is what you do.
你的新裁縫是誰
Who's your new tailor?
總得打扮得像樣
You gotta look the part.
他們什么時候做出決定
So, when do they decide
你瘋沒瘋
whether you're crazy or not?
因為如果你沒瘋
Because if you're not,
你應該來為我們工作
you should come work for us.
我們
Us?
你不也就才在那兒工作了五分鐘嗎
Have you been working there for about five minutes?
其實都一個月了
It's been a month, actually.
他還尸骨未寒呢
So his body wasn't even cold.
他也會希望如此的
It's what he would have wanted.
安德伍德基金會基本上將會參照
The Underwood Foundation was basically gonna be modeled after
謝潑德自由基金會來建設
the Shepherd Freedom Foundation.
我不需要這份工作
I don't need the job.
作為認罪殺人犯  你還挺自信啊
Well, for a confessed murderer, you're pretty confident.
我就要被赦免了
I'm about to be pardoned.
什么
Pardon?
你真覺得她會赦免你
You really think that she's gonna give you one?
你還是那樣  什么都不知道
As usual, you don't know what the fuck you're talking about.
他在加夫尼下葬時  出席的人數
You know, there wasn't the kind of crowd that you'd expect for him
沒有按說該有的那么多
down there in Gaffney.
他本想葬在阿靈頓公墓的
He wanted to be buried in Arlington.
而不是挨著他父親
Not next to his father.
他妻子可不是這么說的
That's not what his wife said.
告訴我
Tell me something.
她哭過嗎
She even shed a tear?
知道嗎
You know...
老實說  我都有點嫉妒
I'm almost envious, to tell you the truth.
就算他進了墳墓
That even beyond the grave,
你也愿意為弗蘭西斯·安德伍德赴湯蹈火
you'd do anything for Francis Underwood.
道格  你給我拿打火機了嗎
Doug, do you have my lighter?
多謝
Much obliged.
那是我想的那個人嗎
Was that who I thought it was?
弗萊德·安博格  他也瘋了
Fred Amburg? He went off the deep end?
每個人都有點問題  賽斯
Everyone has problems, Seth.
尤其是自以為沒有的那些
Especially the ones who think they don't.
-克萊爾  -安奈特
- Claire. - Annette.
你收到我的信了嗎
Oh, did you get my note?
我還沒能鼓起勇氣讀悼念信呢
Oh, I haven't had the courage to read the condolences yet.
很高興看到你終于出來活動了
It's good to see you finally out and about.
你受了多少苦啊
Oh, what you've been through.
你最了解了
You know all about it.
很長一段時間里  我假裝他還活著
Well, for a long time, I pretended he was still alive.
只是出城了
Out of town.
是我們的兒子鄧肯挽救了我
It was our son Duncan that really saved me.
當然了  我們結婚可遠沒有
Of course, we weren't married anywhere near
你和弗蘭克那么久
as long as you and Frank.
克萊爾·黑爾
Claire Hale.
九年前
Nine years.
晚春
Late spring,
太陽谷
Sun Valley.
你一點沒變
You look exactly the same.
城市催人老
Well, it's cities that age you,
我總跟人那么說
it's what I tell everyone.
希望你不介意
I hope you don't mind
跟幾位我們最好的朋友打招呼
saying hello to a few of our closest friends.
他們就是來喝杯雞尾酒
They're just here for a cocktail before the--
等著太陽落山后  其余的客人到來
the sun goes down and the rest of the party shows up.
我妹妹的煙火秀算是成了個傳統了
My sister's fireworks show have become a bit of a tradition.
別擔心  他們會保密的
Don't worry. They know how to be discreet.
斯考特剛收購了奈克西斯安保
Scotty here just got his hands on Nexis Security.
聽說你還要就此事跟副總統談
I heard you are speaking to the vice president about this.
就是一家維和公司
It's a company of peacekeepers, mostly.
有構建國際合作的大潛力
Oh, tremendous potential to create global partnerships.
是你丈夫幫我談妥了協議
Your husband helped me secure the deal.
我本想拉他進董事會的
I wanted to bring him onto the Board.
比爾還說...
Bill was saying...
是啊  我還說呢
Yes, I was just saying.
他們為什么要在
Why in the world do they play
由柴科夫斯基創作
紀念1812年俄國人民擊退拿破侖大軍的入侵
作品以曲中的炮火聲聞名  一些演出中還會真用大炮
煙火秀上演奏《1812序曲》
the "1812 Overture" at a fireworks show?
那可是徹頭徹尾的俄國曲子
It's Russian, for Chrissakes, in every sense.
這是塔比莎
This is Tabitha.
彼得斯  我知道
Peters, I know.
弗蘭克
Frank...
-他今天本來也會到的吧  -是啊
- Wasn't he planning to be here today? - He was.
你肯定很想他
You must miss him terribly.
我曾多次跟他進行過長時間的激烈對話
I had some long and hard-fought conversations with him.
他本想幫我解決內華達州那邊
He was going to help me resolve this AFL-CIO thing
曠日持久的勞聯-產聯的問題
that's been going on forever out in Nevada,
當然了  是在你的幫助下
with your help, of course.
工會如果阻擋創新
When the union stands in the way of innovation,
就是自尋死路
it's sentencing itself to death.
我很欣賞你堅持與黨派站在一起
I do admire the way you hang on to your party.
如此忠誠
Your loyalty.
這是真的嗎  據說南茜·蓋拉格中將
Did I hear that Lieutenant General Nancy Gallagher
今天稍后會與你一同露面
will be appearing with you later today?
我認為她能是個好候選人
I think she'd make an excellent candidate,
如果她決定競選的話
if she decides to run, of course.
她絕對會的
Oh, she's going to run.
總統日程很緊
The president is on a tight schedule.
失陪
Excuse me.
這真令人沒想到
Well, this is a surprise.
你知道中西部的人不喜歡意料之外的事
You know how Midwesterners feel about those.
別聽他的  你也該出來了
Oh, don't listen to him. It's about time you came out.
我們似乎有事要談
Seems we have some things to discuss.
是啊
Yeah.
就這場特別選舉來說  克萊爾
Well, as far as this special election is concerned, Claire,
你要知道即將退休的蓋拉格女士
you need to know that the soon-to-be-retiring Miss Gallagher
是絕對不行的
is out of question.
我很高興我們都喜歡
And I'm happy to see we're both fans
《獨立宣言》
of the Declaration of Independence,
天賦人權什么的
unalienable rights and all that.
但你待會兒要發表的演講里寫著...
But it says down here in the speech you're gonna give later--
我支持蓋拉格女士
Miss Gallagher has my support.
我相信馬克表達了我們的擔憂
I believe Mark conveyed our concerns.
希望他也表達了我的
And communicated mine, I hope.
她褪去軍裝就是個支持大政府的民主黨
She's a tax and spend Democrat underneath that uniform.
-是簡歷卓越的愛國者  -克萊爾
- A patriot with a pristine resume. - Claire.
而且高調反對讓私人承包商
Who is very vocal about keeping private contractors
-插手美軍行動  -就算作為協商籌碼
- away from US military operations. - Even as a negotiating point,
也有比她強的
you can do better than her.
我厭倦了你的拖延  總統女士
And I am tired of these delays, Madam President.
你該說到做到了
It is time for you to deliver.
-你丈夫和我有協議的  -弗蘭西斯死了
- Your husband and I had an agreement. - Francis is dead.
-我們得到了承諾  -不是我給的
- Promises were made. - Not by me.
就像你一樣  我也想自己談協議
Just like you, I like to negotiate my own agreements.
別搞錯了
And make no mistake about it,
中將并不是個例外
the lieutenant general is not an anomaly.
我知道  我看到了你的中期選舉候選人
I know that. I've seen your list of candidates for the midterms--
是啊  大都是女人
Yes, mostly women.
我才不管他們是男是女
I don't care what sex they are.
另外  沒人比我更喜歡女人了
And for the record, nobody loves women more than me.
但你的候選人名單  會拖垮這個國家
But this slate of yours, it will bankrupt the country.
會讓我們倒退一代  會完全...
They will set us back a generation. They will completely--
支持我  和我的立場
Support me and what I stand for.
那是什么
And what is that?
-得了  比爾  -不  你說啊
- Oh, come on, Bill. - No, no. Tell me.
我想聽聽  你的使命是什么
I wanna know. What's your mission?
-我想知道你的綱領是什么  -得了
- I wanna know what your platform is. - Oh, please.
我知道你想一下肅清華府
I know you'd like to drown DC all at once.
但我這就告訴你  我不會允許的
But I'm gonna tell you right now, I cannot let that happen.
我依然相信政府
I still believe in government
相信它有能力改善其公民的日常生活
and its ability to make the everyday lives of its citizens better.
-嗯  -你不想支持我的候選人
- Yeah. - You don't wanna support my slate,
好啊
that's fine.
-克萊爾  -我只要求你別礙事
- Claire... - All I ask is stay out of the way.
你桌上有一份法案
There's a bill sitting on your desk.
這份法案耗時數年
A bill that took years...
耗費財力才獲得通過
and money to get passed.
你簽署了
You sign that,
我就知道我在白宮里有朋友
and I know I got a friend in the White House.
如果你不簽
If not...
-那我就沒有  -夠了
- Then I don't. - Enough.
有她在  你是不會有好果子吃的
Nothing good happens to you when she's around.
相信我
Nothing.
你為什么贊助了弗蘭西斯
Why did you come out for Francis?
他的基金會
For his foundation?
我沒覺得你真喜歡過他
I don't think you ever really liked him.
可能從未尊重過他  為什么現在支持他
Probably never respected him. Why back him now?
因為他把你給了我們
Because he gave us you.
告訴我們的朋友們  我會趕上下來看煙火的
Tell our friends I'll be back down in time for the fireworks.
你要知道  我一直喜歡弗蘭克
Just so you know, I always liked Frank.
喜歡他的絕望
His desperation.
很遺憾你不能留下
I'm sorry you can't stay.
我很喜歡組織我們的煙火秀
I do enjoy curating our little show.
我出行時收集了各種煙火彈
I collect a variety of fireworks shells as I travel.
意大利  西班牙  中國
Italy, Spain, China.
你知道最難做的色彩是什么嗎
Do you know what the hardest color to make is?
-紅色嗎  -不  紅色很簡單
- Red? - No, red's easy.
白色也很簡單
White's easy.
是藍色
It's blue.
銅和溫度的化學調劑很難弄
Very tricky chemistry involving copper and heat.
真正的亮藍色是非常不好做的
A truly bright blue is extremely elusive.
不管弗蘭西斯承諾了什么  做了什么
Whatever Francis promised or did...
都跟他一起入土了
is buried with him.
我知道
No, I know.
我們都得對他放手
We all need to let him go.
從頭做起
Start from some kind of scratch.
但你肯定很難安吧
Though it must haunt you,
他就在床上你身旁長眠不起
the fact that he died next to you in bed.
親愛的
Hon...
耐心點
be patient.
你是說  她不喜歡這名字嗎
Are you saying, she doesn't like the name?
我覺得她認為名字不夠完整
I think she finds it incomplete.
《綜合安全法案》有什么不好
What's wrong with the Comprehensive Safety Act?
那《綜合化學安全法案》呢
Comprehensive Chemical Safety Act?
也可以再回去用《精簡安全法案》
Or we could go back to the Smarter Safety Act.
她會更喜歡"精簡"嗎
Would she like "smarter" better?
不行  得有個好縮寫
No, we need a good acronym.
副總統先生
Mr. Vice President?
馬克
Mark?
嗯  是啊
Yeah. Agreed.
我們還曾考慮過《不安全監管廢止法案》
At one point, we talked about the Repeal Unsafe Regulation Act.
如果能再加個L開頭的就是"農村"了
That's RURAL if we come up with an L.
立法嗎
Legislation?
那跟其他的湊不到一起去
That doesn't make sense with the rest of it.
"農村"這詞不好念  "安全"更好
"RURAL" is too hard to say. "SAFE" is good.
安全  未來
Safety. Future.
-"未來"好  -聯邦綜合有毒危險物...
- I like "FUTURE." - Federal Universal Toxic and Unsafe...
-去監管法案  -好
- Regulation Eradication. - Okay.
-那就《未來法案》了  -可以
- The FUTURE Act. - That could work.
可以問一下  副總統先生
May I ask, Mr. Vice President,
除了名字她還有其他疑慮嗎
does her hesitation go beyond the name?
她會想通的  我猜...
She'll come around. I'm guessing...
到今天晚上吧
by the end of the day.
因為不管是什么名字
Because in one form or another,
這份法案已經在她桌上放了...
this bill has been on her desk since--
她會簽的  亨利
She'll sign it, Henry.
比爾
Bill.
你要我做什么
What do you want me to do?
把她從自己的軍事基地拽回來嗎
Yank her from her own military base?
在人類大事件的過程中  當一個人
When, in the course of human events, it becomes necessary
有必要解除將他們與另一個人
for one people to dissolve the political bands
聯系在一起的政治紐帶時
which have connected them with another,
你得當機立斷
you just have to do it.
切斷關系
Sever the relationship.
我們國家的立國文獻
Our nation's founding document,
《獨立宣言》
the Declaration of Independence--
美國的獨立
America's independence--
是經過艱苦斗爭贏來的
was hard-fought and hard-won.
你還在聽嗎
Are you still there?
我們的國父構想了一個自由國度
Our Founding Fathers imagined a nation that was free.
擺脫專制
Free from despotism.
擺脫暴政
Free from absolute tyranny.
擺脫國王壓迫
Free from an oppressive king.
你想弗蘭西斯了嗎
Do you miss Francis?
暴君有多種多樣
Tyrants come in many forms.
從美國政治寡頭
From the American oligarchs
企圖改變社會根本
trying to change the very fabric of our society,
到在海外叫囂的獨裁者
to autocrats threatening from abroad.
我們每個人都要維護我們的命運
Now, each one of us has to defend our destiny.
在我看來
And as I see it,
抵抗暴政是戰爭的唯一合理理由
the fight against tyranny is the only justification for war.
我作為總統的頭一百天很艱難
My first 100 days as president have been difficult.
我失去了丈夫
I lost my husband.
我們本來正要慶祝結婚30周年
We were about to celebrate 30 years together.
但我了解他的心愿
But I know what he would want.
他會希望我停止哀傷  繼續生活
For me to stop mourning and carry on.
在南茜·蓋拉格中將這樣的女性的幫助下
With the help of women like Lieutenant General Nancy Gallagher,
我的任期將充滿實干
my presidency will not rest.
南茜深深激勵了我
Nancy has been an inspiration to me.
她是不倦的勇士
A tireless warrior.
我向她也向你們保證
I promise her and all of you
我會為我們的民主國家
that I will work on behalf of the rights
這241年間所贏得的權利和自由而奮斗
and freedoms earned over the last 241 years of our democracy.
當我看著今天
As I look into the eyes
站在我面前的這些勇敢戰士們的眼睛
of you brave soldiers standing before me today...
是這樣的
Here's the thing.
我此刻無比驕傲
I'm feeling so proud right now.
為做你們的三軍統帥驕傲
Proud to be your Commander-in-Chief.
不管弗蘭西斯這五年來對你們說了什么
Whatever Francis told you the last five years,
一個字都別信
don't believe a word of it.
我們國家已經241歲了  朋友們
Our country is 241 years old, my friends.
我們祝這個偉大國家生日快樂吧
Let's wish this great nation a happy birthday.
跟我一起說
Say it with me.
生日快樂  美國
Happy birthday, America!
Happy Birthday, America!
我們的情況會有所不同
It's going to be different for you and me.
再來一次
One more time.
我要對你說實話
I'm going to tell you the truth.
生日快樂  美國
Happy Birthday, America.
-謝謝你的服役  -謝謝
- Thank you for your service. - Thank you.
謝謝你的服役
Thank you for your service.
-謝謝你的服役  -謝謝
- Thank you for your service. - Thank you.
我希望你們知道我有多高興能來見見
I want you to know how wonderful it is to be here and meet
你們這些新兵
all of you new recruits.
謝謝你
So, thank you.
謝謝你的服役
Thank you for your service.
-謝謝  -謝謝  女士
- Thank you. - Thank you, ma'am.
謝謝你的服役  你是哪來的  二等兵
Thank you for your service. Where are you from, private?
卡拉馬祖  總統先生
Kalamazoo, Mr. President.
-抱歉  總統女士  -沒事的
- Excuse me, Madam President. - That's quite all right.
我其實討厭"女士"這個詞
I actually hate "Madam."
讓我覺得自己是管理妓院的老鴇
Makes me sound like I'm running a brothel
不是在管理國家
and not a country.
-謝謝你的服役  -謝謝  總統女士
- Thank you for your service. - Thank you, Madam President.
謝謝你的服役
Thank you for your service.
你是哪來的  伯頓二等兵
And where are you from, Pvt. Burton?
南本德  女士
South Bend, ma'am.
我愛印第安納州
Oh, I love Indiana.
我是在您上任前不久入伍的
I enlisted right before you took office.
我向你和美國所有女性保證
Well, I promise you and every woman in this country
在我任期內
that during my presidency
會確保《平權修正案》的關鍵部分
the key components of the Equal Rights Amendment
終能獲得通過
will finally pass.
我會確保這一點的
I'm going to make sure of it.
我希望你知道我支持你
I want you to know I support you.
你制定好計劃了嗎
Do you even have a plan?
你說什么
What did you say?
一個不會把我們都害死的計劃
One that won't get us all killed?
天吶
Oh, man...
如果我是個男人你還會這么問我嗎
Would you have asked me that if I were a man?
總統女士
Madam President!
請回答一個問題
One question, please!
我們還有多久能上飛機
How much longer till we get to the plane?
還有25分鐘左右  總統女士
Just another 25 minutes or so, Madam President.
好  謝謝
Okay, thank you.
該死
Shit!
-她中槍了嗎  -趴下  趴下
- Is she shot? - Stay down, stay down!
有人開槍  有人開槍
Shots fired! Shots fired!
你沒事吧  總統女士
Are you okay, Madam President?
-你沒事吧  -沒事
- Are you all right? - Yes.
孤星安全
Lone Star is safe.
先生  剛有人企圖行刺總統
Sir, someone just tried to kill the president.
我剛收到警報  她沒事吧
I just got the alert. Is she all right?
這邊請
This way.
林肯
Lincoln,
加菲爾德  麥金利
Garfield, McKinley,
肯尼迪
Kennedy.
刺殺成功  一共四起
Successful assassinations, total of four.
企圖刺殺  是九起嗎
The attempts-- Nine?
杰克遜  兩個羅斯福
Jackson, both Roosevelts.
特魯門  福特兩次
Truman. Ford twice.
里根
Reagan...
第一任安德伍德  還有...
the first Underwood and...
我得說  那個企圖殺我的人
I will say, whoever tried to kill me,
事與愿違了
perversely,
這是100天以來  我第一次真正感到受尊重
it's the first sign of real respect I've gotten in 100 days.
有人企圖殺她
Somebody tried to kill her.
比爾
Bill.
也難怪吧
Can you blame them?
安德伍德夫婦都挺耳背的
The Underwoods have always been hard of hearing.
她不是他
She's not him.
是啊
No, no.
她的確不是
She is not.
這你最清楚了
You know that better than anyone.
公開了嗎
Is it public?
被特勤局保密了  據說是標準程序
Secret Service shut it down. Standard procedure, apparently.
威脅會招致威脅
Threats beget threats.
比爾
Bill...
是你搞的嗎
were you behind this?
我們要錯過煙火了
We're gonna miss the show.
-你們好嗎  -總統女士
- How are y'all? - Madam President.
真抱歉
Hi, I'm so sorry.
我想為延遲出發表示道歉
I want to apologize for the late departure.
我知道你們都還有家人和慶典在等著你們
I know you all have families and festivities waiting.
總統女士  我可以問問發生了什么嗎
Madam President, may I ask what happened?
因為安全原因  "野獸"總統專車改道了
The Beast was re-routed due to security concerns.
很正常的
It's pretty routine.
我知道我已經挺久沒來過后面了
I know it's been a while since I've been back here.
我想祝大家國慶節快樂
I just wanted to wish you all a very happy Fourth,
雖然你們要明天才能慶祝了
even if you're gonna be celebrating it on the fifth.
真抱歉
I'm so sorry.
你的講話  之后...
Your speech, afterwards with--
是啊  那名新兵
Yes, the new recruit.
如果一名新兵  尤其還是女兵
If a new recruit, especially a female one,
不能表達自己的看法
can't speak her mind,
那我真不知我們生活在什么樣的國家里了
I don't know what kind of country we actually are.
如果你們沒啤酒了一定要說
And be sure to tell us if you run out of beer.
因為我敢肯定我們還有幾箱
Because I am sure there's a couple of cases
是卡特政府時期留下的
left over from the Carter administration.
你是新來的
And you're new.
是的  女士  梅樂蒂·科魯茲
Yes, ma'am. Melody Cruz.
我是首都電視的
I'm with Beltway Television.
希望大家對你還算熱情
Well, I hope everyone is making you feel at home.
很熱情
Very much so.
很榮幸終于見到了您
It's an honor to finally meet you.
我有點激動了  抱歉
I'm a bit overwhelmed, sorry.
-沒事  我不咬人  -我知道
- Don't worry, I don't bite. - No, I know.
很奇怪  我本該采訪您丈夫的
It's strange, I was supposed to interview your husband.
本來安排在他死后的幾天
It was scheduled for a few days after he died.
本來會是一篇獨家專訪
It was going to be an exclusive.
我們已做了幾次預采訪
We'd had a number of pre-interviews.
也說定了一些問題
Questions we'd agreed on.
什么樣的問題
Questions like?
比如  總統會赦免他嗎
Like, was the president going to pardon him?
以及何時
And when?
你會嗎  甚至是在他死后
Will you? Even now, posthumously?
我知道你跟《紐約觀察家》做了專訪
I know you did an exclusive with The New York Examiner,
但我猜那只會停留于表面
but I'm guessing that's only going to scratch the surface.
我相信你還有更多想說的
I bet you have more to say
-關于你的婚姻狀況  -小姐
- about the state of your marriage-- - Miss...
科魯茲小姐  是吧
Cruz, is it?
不知道有人跟你說過沒有
I don't know if anyone's told you,
但總統來飛機這一區時
but when the president visits this part of the plane,
一般是默認為不做記錄的
it's usually considered off the record.
但等我們落地了  你有什么問題
But you can ask my press secretary anything you like
都可以問我的新聞發言人
once we're back on the ground.
你今晚尤其地安靜
You're especially quiet this evening.
或許我有點焦躁
Maybe I'm a little agitated.
我們的病人對煙火的反應都不佳
Our patients don't do too well when it comes to fireworks.
抱歉
Pardon me.
怎么了
Yes?
我不明白我們會面時  你為什么還開著它
I don't understand why you leave that on when we're meeting.
反正你也不會說點什么新東西
Well, it's not like you're saying anything different or new.
你照本宣科的執著都堪稱可敬了
Your dedication to your script would be admirable
只是這太讓人擔心
if it weren't so concerning.
再過幾周  我就要出席一場聽證會
In a few weeks, I'll be appearing at a hearing
就你的心理狀態作證
regarding your state of mind
至于你的供認
and when it comes to your confession,
有罪之人也會時不時改變說辭
even a guilty man changes his story now and then.
你聽命于誰
Who do you answer to?
你為誰工作
I mean, who do you work for?
你
You.
至少該是這意思
That's the idea, anyway.
每個人都有老板的
Everybody works for somebody.
我曾經的老板是一個不肯認輸的人
I worked for a man who refused to fail.
我尊重那點
I respected that.
也很感激
I appreciated it.
沒有他我早死了
I'd be dead without him.
為什么
Why?
我原本是一個議員的助理
I was working as an aide for a congressman.
他理想化又天真
He was idealistic and naive.
一看就沒有連任的命
Had one-term written all over him.
但我需要份工作  需要個去處
But I needed a job, a place to be.
我當時在勉強支撐
I was barely keeping it together.
弗蘭西斯和我在一場活動上相識
Francis and I met at some function.
就是那種站著的活動
You know, the kind you stand up at.
我不知道他怎么知道的  但我車里有八瓶酒
I don't know how he knew, but I had eight bottles in my trunk.
那晚他找到我家時  我已經喝了四瓶
I got through four that night when he came to my door.
我不記得多少了
I don't remember much.
都很模糊了
Not clearly.
他帶我回了他家
He took me to his home.
但克萊爾...
But Claire...
弗蘭西斯幫我戒了酒
Francis got me dry.
我抖得好厲害  我以為自己會死
I shook so badly I thought I was gonna die.
等我終于戒掉了
And then when I was finally got clean,
他給了我第一份工作
he gave me my first job.
做助理嗎
As an aide?
算是吧
Sort of.
他叫我去找愛荷華州的凱爾議員談談
He asked me to go talk to Congressman Kyle from Iowa.
談什么
To what end?
說服他
To persuade him.
我做到了
And I did.
但克萊爾...
But Claire...
她對待他的方式
The way she treated him,
不論是生前還是死后
in life and in death...
但為他那樣的人工作總要付出代價
But you pay a price, when you work for somebody like him.
欠下人情債
Somebody you owe.
我一個親近的人死于了車禍
Somebody close to me died in a car accident.
所以我才違反了軟禁協議
That's how I broke the terms of my house arrest.
我去看她的車禍現場了
I went to see the site of her wreck.
場面很難看  就在路邊
It was twisted on the side of the road.
我站在那里
I just stood there.
事故嗎
An accident?
他們說是的
So they said.
佐伊·巴恩斯呢
And Zoe Barnes?
我殺了她
I killed her.
為了總統
For the president.
以前他贏了就會這么敲
That's what he used to do when he won.
他給你留下了什么
What did he leave you with?
弗蘭西斯給我的最后一樣東西
Last thing that Francis gave me was
是他桌上的拆信刀
the letter opener from his desk.
是我選的  但是
I mean, I chose it, but...
或許該說他最后給我的一樣東西  是一句道歉
But I guess really the last thing he gave me was an apology.
他死的那晚我跟他說過話
I spoke to him the night he died.
我的任期將充滿實干
My presidency will not rest.
南茜深深激勵了我
Nancy has been an inspiration to me.
她是不倦的勇士
A tireless warrior.
我向她也向你們保證
I promise her and all of you
我會為我們的民主國家
that I will work on behalf of the rights
這241年間所贏得的權利和自由而奮斗
and freedoms earned over the last 241 years of our democracy.
暴君有多種多樣
Tyrants come in many forms...
可悲
Pathetic.
從美國政治寡頭企圖改變
From the American oligarchs trying to change the very...
你真不用休息一兩個小時...
Are you sure you don't want to take an hour or two to--
馬克  我在白宮呢
Mark. I'm inside the White House.
總統辦公室里只有你我  除非你帶槍了
There's only two of us in the Oval, so unless you're packing,
這對我真的是最安全的地方了
it's literally the safest place I can be.
我沒帶槍  總統女士
Well, I'm not packing, Madam President,
但沒人會怪你休息一會兒  喘口氣的
but no one would fault you for taking a breath for a minute.
我氣喘得很勻
I'm breathing just fine.
我們能把這事保密嗎
Can we keep news of this contained?
我已經采取了一切可能措施
I've taken every possible step, I think.
他是什么人
So who is he?
他們在路上進行了采證
Well, they did forensics on the route.
并與空中安保進行了溝通
Compared notes with the aerial detail.
國土安全部和聯調局都已介入
Homeland Secretary and the Bureau were brought in.
他就沒有離開他開槍的地方
He never left the place he took the shot from.
你能直截了當地回答我嗎
Can you answer a single question directly and simply?
他一槍爆了自己的頭
He shot himself in the head
用的是他自己的美軍標準配發手槍
with his own US military-issued handgun.
我們確定槍手就是他
And we're sure he's the one?
是  支持民兵組織  反政府
Yeah. Pro-militia. Anti-government.
去年被開除軍籍  有所有典型特征
Dishonorably discharged last year. All the typical markers.
特勤局確定是他
Secret Service is confident.
聯調局也在調查了
And the Bureau's investigating.
比爾·謝潑德怎么拿到我的講話的
How did Bill Shepherd get his hands on my speech?
什么
What?
媒體往往幾小時前就能拿到
Well, the press usually gets it hours before.
想拿到一份應該不難吧
It wouldn't be that hard to access a copy, I guess.
我今天不會簽那個的
I won't be signing that today.
你去那兒宣布你的獨立
You went there to declare your independence,
也宣了戰
and you declared war.
那是個錯誤
That was a mistake.
不  錯誤是我沒雇幕僚長
No, the mistake was I didn't hire a chief of staff,
就有些事疏于管理
and things are slipping through the cracks.
這我就不能認同了
That's where I have to disagree with you.
我們得保持一個小圈子
We need to keep this circle small.
弗蘭西斯提醒過我小心你
You know, Francis warned me about you.
我向你保證  我為你效力  總統女士
I assure you, I serve at your pleasure, Madam President.
你不能再在我的辦公室里開不帶我的會了
You need to stop meeting in my office without me.
是  女士
Yes, ma'am.
是特勤局牽頭調查的
Secret Service took the lead.
但你相信這個說法嗎
But do you believe the theory?
是一個不滿的退役士兵沖我開了槍
That it was a disgruntled service person who took a shot at me?
警方調查部認為是
PID does.
我問你怎么想
I'm asking what you think.
這要看這是警告還是真正的刺殺企圖
It depends if it was a warning or an actual attempt.
看他的準頭
Given the accuracy,
槍手應該有足夠的情報知道
the shooter would have been informed enough to know
.50子彈無法穿透"野獸"
that a .50 caliber round wouldn't penetrate the Beast.
我認為他就是想嚇你
I think he wanted to scare you.
替人辦事
On behalf of someone.
有很多人會對在任總統發出威脅
Lots of people make threats against sitting presidents.
我開始認為弗蘭西斯是被謀殺的
I'm starting to believe Francis was murdered.
他死前
Before he died,
曾與一些很有勢力的人結了盟
he aligned himself with some very powerful people.
我認為他們與他反目  并想殺死他
And I think they turned on him, and they wanted him dead,
我覺得他們還想殺我
and I think they want me dead, too.
你覺得這聽上去瘋狂嗎
Do you think that sounds crazy?
不  女士
No, ma'am.
但我覺得我們該叫鮑曼特別探員來
But I think we need to bring in Special Agent Bowman--
這些人  這些大家族
Of these people, these powerful families,
他們倡議解散情報機構
they advocate dismantling intelligence agencies.
中情局  聯調局  國土安全部
CIA, FBI, Homeland.
你知道吧
You know that, right?
-女士  -我們現在
- Ma'am-- - We cannot bring
不能再拉上任何其他人
anyone else in at the moment.
我指望你了
I'm relying on you
我知道我丈夫當初就能指望你
the way I know my husband could.
請你去查查看
So, please see what you can find.
你被稱作過納特嗎
Is it ever Nate
還是一直叫納森
or always Nathan?
納森
Nathan.
就像弗蘭西斯
Like Francis.
至少我總那么叫他
For me, anyway.
你跟道格·斯坦普談過了嗎
Oh, have you spoken to Doug Stamper?
沒有
No.
我好擔心他
I'm so worried about him.
他做了令白宮每個人都不恥的事
He did things no one in this White House should be proud of.
媽媽
Hey, Mom.
你那邊有多少人
How many people do you have there?
不多
Not many.
至少沒什么有趣的人
Nobody that interesting, anyway.
她的基地之行
Her visit to the base.
關于獨立的講話
Independence speech,
甚至士兵的出言不遜對她都很有利
even the naughty soldier is playing well for her.
她的魅力不減
Her charmed life persists.
告訴比爾舅舅我們該加把勁
Tell Uncle Bill we should step up.
我可以操縱輿論  削減她的魅力
I can manage the narrative. De-charm her.
他不會喜歡那樣的
He won't like that.
反正這一切都不會讓他高興的
He's not going to like any of it,
有什么區別呢
so what's the difference?
-還是不好吧  -媽媽  就去說說吧
- I don't know. - Mom, just say the word.
相信我
Trust me.
我回復你之前什么都別做
Don't do a thing until I get back to you.
都看不出這里還是華府
Can't even tell you're still in DC.
這座城市里有些地方永遠都會是個秘密
There are parts of this city that will always remain a secret.
順說  我覺得我短期內
I don't think I'll be welcome back
不會再被邀請加入白宮記者團了
in the White House press pool anytime soon, FYI.
沒關系
Doesn't matter.
她不肯跟我談
She won't speak to me.
-采訪不可能的  經過...  -她會答應的
- An interview? Not after-- - She will.
今晚  他第一次主動開口
Tonight, for the first time, he was forthcoming.
但還堅稱他有罪
But still saying he's guilty?
是的  一如既往
Yeah, as always.
他提到格雷森先生的名字了嗎
And did he mention Mr. Grayson by name?
沒有  他只是更難過了
No. He was just more distressed.
他在惡化嗎
So he's getting worse?
也可能是好轉  他可算開口了
Or better, he's finally talking.
但要說短期內讓他離開那里
But the idea of his leaving the facility anytime soon,
還是不可能的  這是為了他好
that's still out of the question. I mean, for his own good.
他要么真犯了罪
He's either guilty of the crime
-要么認罪是在發瘋  -總統女士
- or psychotic for admitting to it. - Madam President,
謝潑德女士打到白宮來了
Miss Shepherd is on the White House line.
或許該給他開抗精神病藥了
Well, maybe it's time to give him one of the antipsychotics.
或許吧  但我們得考慮他的癮史
Possibly. But we'd have to consider his history of addiction.
對了  回答你的問題
By the way, in answer to your question,
是一把拆信刀
it was a letter opener,
弗蘭西斯從桌上拿來送他的最后一樣東西
the last thing that Francis gave him from his desk.
有情況再通知我  查爾斯
Keep me posted, Charles.
謝謝你
And thank you.
不客氣
Sure.
你準備好了嗎
Are you prepared?
什么
Excuse me.
你不記得了嗎  安多弗
Don't you remember? Andover?
我們的預科學校玩笑
Our prep school joke?
我準備當掉測試
I'm prepared to fail the test.
你還好嗎
Are you all right?
抱歉這么晚打來  我聽說了今天的事
I'm sorry to call so late. I-- I heard about what happened today.
這些事總是不脛而走
These things have a tendency to leak out.
我擔心你
I'm worried about you.
車隊玻璃是防彈的
It's bulletproof, the motorcade glass.
他們抓到那男人了嗎
Did they catch the guy?
你怎么知道是男人
How do you know it's a guy?
總是男人嘛
It's always a guy, right?
比爾希望修改我講話的哪一部分
What was it Bill wanted adjusted in my speech?
就是關于
Something about...
自由的
freedom.
我惦記著你  克萊爾
You're in my thoughts, Claire.
謝謝
Thank you.
他還在我們身邊  是吧
He's still with us, don't you think?
誰
Who?
弗蘭克
Frank.
幸好他死前我們能跟他共度那么多的時光
We're so glad we got to spend so much time with him before he died.
他對我們說了些很有趣的事
He told us some fascinating things.
我一直在想他
He's been on my mind.
比爾和我幾天前總算去了趟加夫尼
Bill and I finally went down to Gaffney a few days ago...
前去悼念
to pay our respects.
克萊爾
Claire!
我不該讓他們那么做的
I shouldn't have let them.
對不起
I'm sorry.
出來吧
Come on out now.
你還在嗎
Are you still there?
在啊
Yes.
救命
Help!
我知道
I know.
你想知道他究竟發生了什么
You want to know what really happened to him.
弗蘭西斯那樣的男人不會就那么死去
A man like Francis doesn't just die.
那就...
That would be...
怎么說的來著
what's the word?
"太巧了"
"Convenient."
在內政  外交  經濟  社會等各種議題上
共和黨和民主黨都持不同的觀點和立場
但兩黨最核心的分歧  在于對聯邦政府的定位不同
民主黨的基本信念是"大政府能夠辦大事  辦好事"
而共和黨則認為應該限制政府的權力
大政府必然帶來官僚主義和腐敗
共和黨總統里根曾說
"政府不是解決問題的答案  政府就是問題所在"
因此  共和黨人反對政府增加稅收  反對加大政府開支
還費盡心機地試圖通過立法放松政府對企業公司的監管
謝潑德兄妹希望克萊爾簽字的法案
就是一個要放松環保監管的法案
"野獸"是美國總統的專車
在現實生活中  美國總統特朗普剛剛更換了自己的座駕
今年9月聯合國大會期間
特朗普乘坐新訂制的"野獸"在紐約街頭飛馳而過
據美國媒體報道  新款"野獸"是由通用公司研發的凱迪拉克
上世紀八十年代前  美國總統專車則一般是林肯
全車重約七千到九千公斤  車身厚20厘米  不僅防彈  還防生化武器
另據NBC報道  這款車還能發射催淚彈  煙霧彈以及向車后路面灑油
車門把手可以釋放高壓電
車內有全套急救設備  一個冰箱里儲備了跟特朗普同血型的血液
車載通訊設備也是最先進的  極端情況下可以下達核攻擊指令
出于安全考慮  總統車隊出行時  會有一模一樣的兩輛"野獸"
根據合同  通用會制造10到12輛這樣的車  總造價一千五百萬美元左右
過去兩年中  關于"美國選民是否有'厭女癥'"的討論一直不斷
在2016年大選中  希拉里·克林頓意外敗給了特朗普
一些媒體和希拉里的粉絲認為  社會觀念上的落后
導致選民無法接受白宮內出現一位女當家
同歐洲一些國家相比  女性在美國政壇的影響力的確有限
目前在聯邦政府和國會中  女性政治人物所占比重只有20%左右
包括3名女性最高法院法官  7名女性內閣部長  50個州中有6名女性州長
百名參議員中有23位女性  435名眾議員中有84名女性
但是希拉里落敗的主要原因  同她的女性身份關系不大
2016大選期間  民調始終顯示她是歷史上最不受歡迎的候選人之一
主要原因是她同老公比爾·克林頓在美國政壇活躍數十年  丑聞不斷
大選過程中又爆出"郵件門"等丑聞  所以記憶力好的選民對她很不買賬
有評論甚至認為特朗普當選的主要原因  正是大家討厭希拉里
2016大選結束后  美國社會中的女性參政意識有了一個井噴
在剛剛結束的中期選舉中  有創紀錄的256名女性候選人參加普選角逐
最后有96名成功進入國會兩院成為女議員
民主黨奪回眾議院控制權后  加州的南希·佩羅西也二度成為女議長
在2020大選中  民主黨內預計會有大量女性候選人參加初選